af.cm 2016-12-01

# Privacy Policy - CenturyLink Cloud

_Updated: March 17th, 2016_

We are strongly committed to protecting the privacy of your personal information. The policies below are applicable to the www.ctl.io website (“Website”) produced and maintained by CenturyLink Cloud (collectively, “CenturyLink Cloud,” “Company,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) and the services and products made available on such Website such as our Client Management section (the “Control Panel”). The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the service for which CenturyLink Cloud’s customers (each, a “Client”) have engaged it. We have established this privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) to let you know the kinds of personal information we may gather during your visit to the Website and during the course of your use of our services and products, why we gather your information, what we use your personal information for, when we might disclose your personal information, and how you can manage your personal information.

Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy apply only to information gathered online by us when you visit our Website, when you sign up to use our services or products in the Client Management section of the Website (the “Control Panel”), when you log into our services, and when you execute programs or scripts on our servers. It does not apply to (1) information that you may submit to us offline, (2) information you store on our services or products, or (3) websites maintained by other companies or organizations to which we may link.

**By visiting our Website or using our services and products, you are accepting the practices described in our Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the Website or our services and products.**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or don’t see your concerns addressed here, you should contact us by email at [privacy@ctl.io](mailto:privacy@ctl.io).

CenturyLink Cloud has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal.

The TRUSTe program does not cover information that may be collected through downloadable software. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this Web site, www.ctl.io and our service platform control.ctl.io.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

CenturyLink Cloud complies with the U.S. – E.U. Safe Harbor framework and the U.S. - Swiss Safe Harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. CenturyLink Cloud has certified that it adheres to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view CenturyLink Cloud’s certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

## What Information About Me Is Collected and Stored?

Company adheres to the highest standards of ethical practices in all of our operations and is dedicated to protecting the privacy of all visitors to our Website and users of our services and products. **Our Privacy Policy is simple: Except as disclosed below, we don't sell, barter, give away, or rent your personal information to any company outside of Company.**

### Personal Information

For purposes of registration and use of our services, we collect identifiable information about you and your authorized users such as subscriber name, subscriber website, user ID, email address, telephone numbers, billing information (such as credit card number), and demographic information such as zip code (“Personal Information”). We also collect and store information that you enter into the Control Panel of the Website or that you provide through our help desk, customer service representatives, or requests for more information. Registration may also be required and Personal Information may also be collected in certain portions of the Website in which you specifically and knowingly provide such information (e.g. blog comments, if any). We also may collect and store information about you that we receive from other sources, to enable us to update and correct the information contained in our database.

More specifically, we collect the following Personal Information in the following circumstances: (1) when you visit our Website, we collect your IP address, HTTP referrer information and requested pages, and we log such information into plain text and SQL databases; (2) when you sign up for our services or products, we collect your IP address, HTTP referrer information, requested pages, username, email address, URLs, billing and mailing addresses, and credit card (number, expiration date, and CCV) or paypal billing information, and we log such information into plain text and SQL databases; (3) if you log into our services via SSH and SFTP, we collect your IP address, reverse DNS information and initial commands, and we log such information into secured local and remote text files and SQL databases; (4) if you execute programs or script on our servers, we collect the user, script name and binaries used, and we log such information into secured local and remote text files and SQL databases; and (5) if you submit issues via email or any other support system, we collect your IP address, username, URLs and email address; (6) if you choose to add new users to your account.

### Anonymous Information

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We do this to improve services we offer you, analytics, and site functionality.

### Tracking Technologies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by CenturyLink Cloud and our partners, affiliates, or analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to remember users’ settings (e.g. language preference) and for authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited. To manage Flash cookies, please click [here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager07.html).

We and third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity use LSOs such as HTML 5 to collect and store information.

Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5 LSOs.

We partner with a third party to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) ). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

### Is Information Collected From Children?

This is not a Website directed to children under the age of 13, and Company does not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13 years of age. If you are under 13 years of age you should not use this Website, and under no circumstance should you send information about yourself to Company. If Company discovers that a child under the age of 13 has provided Company with Personal Information, Company will immediately delete that child’s information from the Website.

### How We Use Your Information?

We use the information we learn from you to help us personalize and continually improve your experience on the Website. We use the information to fulfill support requests, deliver products and services, process payments, communicate with you about products, services, promotional offers, update our records and generally maintain your accounts with us. We also use this information to improve our Control Panel, prevent or detect fraud or abuses of our Website and, as described below, enable third parties to carry out technical, logistical or other functions on our behalf. Except as disclosed in this Privacy Policy, we do not use or disclose information about your individual visits to our Website or your Personal Information collected online to any companies not affiliated with us.

### Customer Service and Feedback

We may use your Personal Information to fulfill support requests, provide customer service/support, track your compliance with the Company’s Acceptable Use Policy, or for feedback purposes (to the extent that is explained when you provide the information). In the event we plan to publicly post any of your Personal Information on the Website, we will request your permission to provide such posting.

### Use of Anonymous Information

We use Anonymous Information to help us determine how people use parts of the Website and who our users are so we can improve our Website and ensure that it is as appealing as we can make it for as many people as possible. We may also use or share Anonymous Information (or other information, other than Personal Information) in any other manner that we deem appropriate or necessary.

### Third-Party Agents

We occasionally have third party agents, subsidiaries, affiliates and partners that perform functions on our behalf, such as marketing, analytics, credit card processing, providing customer service/support, fraud protection, etc. These entities have access to the Personal Information needed to perform their functions and are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality and security of that Personal Information. They are restricted from using, selling, distributing or altering this data in any way other than to provide the requested services to Company.

### Emergency Situations

We may also use or disclose Personal Information if required to do so by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary to (a) conform to applicable law or comply with legal process served on us or the Website; (b) protect and defend the our rights or property, the Website or our users, and © act under emergency circumstances to protect the personal safety of us, our affiliates, agents, or the users of the Website or the public, or respond to a government request. We do not sell your Personal Information to third parties.

### What Steps Are Taken To Keep Personal Information Secure?

We are concerned with the security of the Personal Information associated with you. We have implemented commercially reasonable measures to prevent unauthorized access to your Personal Information. These measures include policies, procedures, employee training, physical access and technical measures relating to data access controls. In addition, we use standard security protocols and mechanisms such as secure socket layer technology (SSL) in the transmission of certain sensitive Personal Information, such as credit card information and login credentials.

While we try our best to safeguard your Personal Information once we receive it, no transmission of data over the Internet or any other public network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at [privacy@ctl.io](mailto:privacy@ctl.io). 

### Data Retention

We comply with the following data retention policies with respect to your Personal Information: (1) we permanently retain in an encrypted format of your billing information; (2) we may permanently retain your forum and weblog contributions; and (3) we may permanently retain your support emails, web logs and accounting logs, though we reserve the right to destroy such information after a period of six months. We will retain and use your Personal Information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your Personal Information to provide you services contact us at [privacy@ctl.io](mailto:privacy@ctl.io).

### Your Obligations to Keep Your Access Rights Secure

You promise to: (a) provide true, accurate, current and complete information about yourself and your business as prompted by the Website's Control Panel (such information being the "Registration Data") and (b) maintain and promptly update the Registration Data to keep it true, accurate, current and complete. If you provide any information that is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, or Company has reasonable grounds to suspect that such information is untrue, inaccurate, not current or incomplete, Company has the right to suspend or terminate your account and refuse any and all current or future use of the Website (or any portion thereof). You are entirely responsible for the security and confidentiality of your password and account. Furthermore, you are entirely responsible for any and all activities that occur under your account. You agree to immediately notify us of any unauthorized use of your account or any other breach of security of which you become aware. You are responsible for taking precautions and providing security measures best suited for your situation and intended use of the services and Website. Please note that anyone able to provide your Personal Information will be able access your account so you should take reasonable steps to protect this information.

If your Personal Information changes, or you wish to deactivate your account, you may correct, delete inaccuracies, or deactivate it by making changes within the user profile section of the Website or by contacting us at [privacy@ctl.io](mailto:privacy@ctl.io). We will respond to your change request within thirty (30) days.

### Information Related to Data Collected through the Control Panel

Company collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose Personal Information it processes.

We collect information for our Clients. If you are a customer of one of our Clients and would no longer like to be contacted by that Client which uses our service, please contact the Client that you interact with directly.

### Service Provider, Sub-Processors/Onward Transfer

Company may transfer Personal Information to companies that help us provide our service. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Privacy Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients.

### Access to Data Controlled by our Clients

Company has no direct relationship with the individuals whose Personal Information it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate Personal Information should direct his query to the relevant Company Client (the data controller). If the Client requests Company to remove the Personal Information, we will respond to their request within thirty (30) days.

### Data Retention

Company will retain Personal Information we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to each Client. Company will retain and use this Personal Information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes and enforce our agreements. 

### What Happens When I Link To or From Another Web Site?

This Website may contain links to other websites operated by affiliates of Company or third parties. Please be advised that the practices described in this Privacy Policy for Company do not apply to information gathered through these other websites. These other sites may also send their own cookies to you, collect your data or solicit your Personal Information. Always be aware of all websites you visit. We are not responsible for the actions and privacy policies of third parties and other websites. We encourage you to be aware of when you leave this Website and read the privacy policies of each and every website that you visit.

### Public Areas, Chat Rooms and Newsgroups

Our Website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at [privacy@ctl.io](mailto:privacy@ctl.io). In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

### Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [privacy@ctl.io](mailto:privacy@ctl.io).

### Social Media Features and Widgets

Our Website includes social media features, such as the Facebook ‘Like’ button, and widgets, such as the ‘Share’ button, or interactive mini-programs that run on our Website (collectively, “Features”). These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our Website, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Features are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Website. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the Privacy Policy of the company providing it.

### Governing Law/Assignment

The Website is published in the United States of America (the “U.S.”). We make every effort to protect the Personal Information of all users of the Website. We attempt to comply with local data protection and consumer rights laws to the extent they may apply to our services. If you are uncertain whether this Privacy Policy conflicts with the applicable local privacy laws where you are located, you should not submit your Personal Information to us.

We may change ownership or corporate organization while providing the Website and services. As a result, please be aware that we may transfer your information to another company that is affiliated with us or with which we have merged or by which we have been acquired. Under such circumstances, Company would to the extent possible require the acquiring party to follow the practices described in this Privacy Policy, as it may be amended from time to time. You will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your Personal Information.

### Notice to European Users

If you are located within the European Union, you should be aware that your Personal Information will be transferred to the U.S. and Canada, the laws of which may be deemed by the European Union to have inadequate data protection. If you are located in a country outside the U.S. and voluntarily submit Personal Information to us, you thereby consent to the general use of such information as provided in this Privacy Policy and to the transfer of that information to, and/or storage of that information in, the U.S.and Canada.

### Changes to This Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the email address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Website prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### How Do I Opt-Out

You may always opt-out of receiving future email messages and newsletters from Company. We provide you with the opportunity to opt-out of receiving communications from us at the point where we request information about you or by following the unsubscribe link located at the bottom of each communication.

### Your California Privacy Rights

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits customers of Company who are California residents to request certain information regarding its disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to [privacy@ctl.io](mailto:privacy@ctl.io.com).

### Contact Us

CenturyLink Cloud  
1100 112th Avenue NE Suite 400  
Bellevue, WA 98004
